I see…
這樣啊
You're an adventurer, huh?
妳是冒險者吧？
Long time ago, I used to dream of being an adventurer too.
很久以前 我也經常夢想成為一名冒險者
It was like any other
不管是誰
stupid dream that kids fantasize about.
小時候都曾經有過這種無聊的夢想
ORIGINAL STORY BY KANEHITO YAMADA / TSUKASA ABE
（原作：山田鐘人，作畫：阿部司）
29 YEARS FROM THE DEATH OF HIMMEL THE HERO
（勇者欣梅爾逝世的29年後）
ALT WOODS IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
（北方諸國，亞魯特森林）
When I was a kid,
我還小的時候
I had a best friend with whom I had many little adventures with.
曾經有個跟我 一起到處探險的至交好友
He was a reckless ball of energy.
他完全就是個體力充沛的莽撞鬼
It was as if he was a gorilla.
跟大猩猩沒兩樣
But he was a kind gorilla who cared about his friends.
但他是那種會在乎朋友的大猩猩
After we had grown up and I had forgotten all about my dream,
長大之後 我把自己的夢想忘得一乾二淨
he invited me to become an adventurer with him.
他卻跑來邀我跟他一起去當冒險者
Back then, if I had taken his hand,
那時我要是抓住了他的手
things would've been different.
也許我的人生就會不一樣了
That was ten years ago already.
說起來都過了十年了
But I still regret it to this day.
至今我仍然後悔那天的事
Why are you telling me this story?
你幹嘛跟我說這段往事呢？
It's almost time for the harvest festival in my village.
我們村子快要舉辦豐收祭了
And my older brother told me to pick wild herbs in the forest
哥哥要我來森林裡摘些野生草藥
so we can cook with them.
準備拿來做飯用
But then…
後來…
I got stuck in a bottomless swamp.
我就掉進這個深不見底的沼澤了
I'm…
我已經…
done for.
完蛋了
But if you take my hand, something may change.
不過，要是妳能抓住我這隻手的話 或許能改變什麼呢
Just a second. I'm contemplating.
你等等，我考慮考慮
What is there to contemplate about at this point?
都這個節骨眼了 妳還有什麼要考慮的？
Your hand is dirty.
你的手很髒
This is no time to be caring about stuff like that.
現在沒時間在意這種小細節吧
And plus, young lady,
而且，小姑娘
adults are all dirty in one way or another.
大人都很骯髒
I've never had to deal with someone who's dirty in a literal sense.
我還沒實際遇到這種真的骯髒的狀況
Can you give me some time?
能再給我一點時間嗎？
I'll try to remember the spell to pull someone out of a bottomless swamp.
我回想一下 從深不見底沼澤把人拉出來的魔法
-Try to hurry. -Let's see…
-盡量快點吧 -我想想喔…
Mistress Frieren,
芙莉蓮大人
did you get all the medicinal herbs?
您採到所有藥草了嗎？
Oh, I remembered it.
我想起來了
Up to here is fine.
送我到這裡就好了
I apologize on behalf of Mistress Frieren.
我代芙莉蓮大人道歉
Don't worry about it.
沒什麼大不了的啦
She saved me in the end.
她最後還是救了我嘛
No, I will make sure
不，我一定會…
to scold her very firmly.
好好說她一頓的
I'm staying out of it.
我可不管喔
Are you sure you don't want to stop by the village?
話說回來 你們真的不順道來村裡坐坐嗎？
We're busy with the harvest festival, but I can at least thank you.
我們正在忙著舉辦豐收祭 但起碼能夠招待你們一下
We want to stock up on materials,
我們打算補充物資
so we want to get to a large town by today.
所以今天之內必須抵達大型城鎮
I see.
這樣啊
Well then, be careful.
那你們路上小心
There are a lot of dangerous, poisonous creatures here.
這一帶有很多危險的有毒生物
-Yeah. -Okay.
-好 -知道了
I got bitten.
我被咬了
Bitten?
被咬了？
Didn't he tell us to be careful? What are you thinking?
他剛剛不是才說要小心點嗎？ 你這是在幹什麼啊？
Anyway, let's stop the bleeding.
總之先止血吧
Oh?
奇怪？
My nose is bleeding.
我流鼻血了
Analyzing types of poison
毒的種類分析
is a spell used by priests, so it's not my forte.
是僧侶用的魔法，我不擅長啊
I'm unfamiliar with this reaction,
這種中毒反應我也沒見過
so the antidotes I have may not work.
所以我手上的解毒劑可能會沒用
It's better to get it checked at a church.
最好是去教會找人看看
Fern, how much longer can you use flight magic?
費倫，妳還能用飛行魔法飛多久？
It uses up a lot of mana,
因為會消耗大量魔力
so 30 minutes would be my limit.
所以最多只能撐三十分鐘吧
We can't make it to town in just 30 minutes.
三十分鐘不夠我們飛到城鎮
Let's return to that village.
折返回先前那個村子吧
I'll carry Stark.
修塔爾克就由我來帶
You're overreacting.
反應過度了吧
I'm fine.
我沒問題啊
Master used to say that poison can be overcome with willpower.
師父總說中毒這種事 靠意志力就能挺過去了
That reminds me…
說起來
Even when he was hit by poisonous arrows that could take down a dragon,
艾冉中了連巨龍都招架不住的毒箭
Eisen was completely fine.
也完全沒事呢
Heiter was absolutely speechless.
海塔都震驚到說不出話來了
-You see? -Actually,
-看吧？ -不
the fact that he was speechless
“震驚到說不出話來”
means Master Eisen was not normal.
就表示艾冉大人已經不是正常人了
And plus, according to Master Heiter,
而且，海塔大人說過
20% of adventurer fatalities are caused by poison.
冒險者的死因有兩成肇因是中毒
Let's hurry.
還是抓緊時間處理吧
I'm really fine.
我真的沒事啊
It's too late.
太遲了
In a few hours, your brain will start to melt
幾個小時內，你的大腦就會開始融化
and drain out from your nose.
然後全部從鼻孔流出來
And you'll die.
最後你就會死掉
That's so scary!
也太可怕了吧！
There's nothing we can do, Father?
沒有我們能做的事了嗎，神父大人？
Normally, it is only treatable in the early stages.
這種毒本來只有在中毒初期能夠治癒
But perhaps my little brother could…
不過我弟弟或許可以…
Brother, do you have a second?
哥哥，有空說句話嗎？
Isn't our new washing bowl a little too small?
新的浴盆是不是太小了點啊？
We have to live modestly.
我們得克勤克儉
This is going too far.
這也克過頭了吧
Nobody else makes things this miniature just to live modestly.
會克勤克儉到這種程度的人 也只有我們家了吧
More importantly, Sein, take a look at this man.
先別管那個了，贊恩 你幫這個人看一下吧
Oh? These are the people
咦？哥哥，就是他們啊
who saved me.
先前救了我的人
What? Did you get bitten by a snake or something?
怎麼了？你這是被蛇還什麼給咬了？
Didn't I say to be careful?
我不是都說了要小心嗎？
Well then, now we're even.
那這樣就兩不相欠了
I'll go help out in the plaza.
哥哥，我去廣場幫忙了
All right.
好
My nosebleed
我的鼻血…
stopped.
停了
I don't detect any poison.
感知不到毒素了
Father, that guy…
神父大人，那個人…
What are your thoughts
妳對我弟弟
on my little brother?
有什麼想法嗎？
That holy symbol around your neck is something
你脖子上掛著的
the Holy City gives to the most outstanding priest outside the city.
是聖都授予地方最傑出僧侶的聖印
You must be an expert in healing.
在治療這方面，你肯定是專家
But he instantly healed someone whom you deemed incurable.
但他卻瞬間治好了 連你都束手無策的毒
It must be a natural talent.
那肯定是與生俱來的天賦
I knew you would be able to tell, Mistress Frieren.
芙莉蓮大人果然好眼力
You know about me?
你知道我的事？
I heard about you from Master Heiter.
我從海塔大人那邊聽過妳的事情
This holy symbol was bestowed upon me by Master Heiter
這是海塔大人從聖都
who came here on a visit from the Holy City.
來這裡訪察時，所授予我的聖印
But in the end, I am nothing but a countryside priest.
但說到底，我不過是個鄉下僧侶罷了
This is the only thing that I can be proud about.
這是我唯一能夠驕傲的地方了
On the other hand,
也就是說
Sein's talent is on another level.
贊恩的才能已經不是我所能及的了
Our parents died early on.
我們父母早早就去世了
So I raised my brother Sein,
是我把弟弟贊恩拉拔長大的
who is much younger than me.
他小我很多歲
When he was a child,
那孩子還小的時候
he used to always say that he wanted to be an adventurer.
經常總說以後想當個冒險者
He didn't want to be
他並不想成為
a priest in an ordinary village like me and do the same thing
像我這樣平凡的鄉下僧侶，每天過著
day after day.
一成不變的生活
He told me that with eyes filled with hopes and dreams.
他那樣跟我說的時候 眼底盡是希望與夢想
But now, he resembles me when I was young.
但現在他卻跟我年輕時一模一樣
He must be bored with life.
想必他的人生一定無聊透頂吧
Please,
拜託妳
will you take him out of this village for me?
這算是我的請求 請妳帶著那孩子離開村子，好嗎？
I'm sure he has just been
我相信那孩子
waiting for someone to give him a nudge.
只是在等有個人能夠推他一把
I'm for it, Frieren.
我贊成，芙莉蓮
It's not that hard of a decision.
這沒什麼好猶豫的吧
I don't want to risk having my brain come out of my nose anymore.
我再也不想遇上 大腦會從鼻子流出來這種事了
It's true that it may be safer
今後如果有個僧侶同行的話
to have a priest with us from here on.
也確實能更讓人安心
Why are you against it, Mistress Frieren?
芙莉蓮大人對他有什麼不滿意嗎？
Maybe it's an aversion to my own kind…
也許是出於對同類的厭惡感吧…
What are you talking about?
在說什麼鬼話啊？
Anyway, I'll recruit him even if I have to do it alone.
無論如何，就算只有我一個 我也要去邀請他加入隊伍
Where is he going?
他要去哪裡？
Apparently, Master Sein spends most of his time in the bar below.
據說贊恩大人 大部分的時間都待在樓下的酒吧
What…
什麼？
Drinking,
喝酒
smoking,
抽菸
gambling…
賭博…
You can't get anymore corrupt than this.
真的是什麼能幹的都幹了呢
This is how you deepen friendships.
這是跟人拉近關係的辦法啊
Want to join, kid?
小子，要加入嗎？
My name is Stark.
我叫修塔爾克
We're looking for a priest.
我們正需要一名僧侶
Want to come with us?
要不要加入我們？
You must be joking.
你是在說笑吧
I'm a priest of this village.
我是這個村子的僧侶
Adventures aren't…
冒險什麼的…
Well, this may be interesting.
不，說不定會很有意思
Have a seat, Stark.
坐吧，修塔爾克
If you can beat me, I'll join your group.
你要是贏了我，我就加入你們
-Really? -Yeah, really.
-真的嗎？ -沒錯，是真的
Stop!
住手啊！
Mistress Frieren,
芙莉蓮大人
it sounds like Master Stark is screaming from below.
聽起來好像是 修塔爾克大人在下面大叫
He's been stripped of all his clothes!
他衣服全被扒光了！
How terrible. Who would do such a thing?
真過分，到底是誰做的好事？
Don't blame me.
可別怪我喔
Adults are all dirty in one way or another.
大人都很骯髒
He's been stripped of all his clothes too!
他衣服也全被扒光了！
The village chief won it all.
村長一個人全贏走了
His skills were out of this world.
他的賭技根本是神鬼等級
Sein…
贊恩…
I heard you're looking for another member?
聽說你們要找新夥伴加入？
Go find someone else.
去找別人吧
You want to be an adventurer, right?
你想成為冒險者吧？
Like I said, that was a long time ago.
我之前也說過 那是很久以前的事情了
It's too late for that.
事到如今還有什麼好說的？
I should have followed after him a long time ago.
我本來早就該出發去追他了
Now I'm just a pathetic old man in nothing but underwear.
現在我不過是個 只剩條內褲的笨蛋大叔而已
Frieren,
芙莉蓮
let's take down the Demon King together.
跟我們一起打倒魔王吧
It's too late for that.
事到如今還有什麼好說的？
I haven't fought an actual demon in more than 500 years.
我都已經有五百年以上 沒有跟魔族對戰過了
I've forgotten how to fight already.
早就忘了該怎麼戰鬥了
I've held back on making a decision for too long.
在下定決心這件事上拖太久了
I was probably scared of fighting the Demon King.
我恐怕是不敢和魔王戰鬥吧
Too much time has passed and there's no turning back.
已經逝去的歲月沒有彌補的餘地
So what, Frieren?
那又怎麼樣，芙莉蓮？
-I'm talking about "now."
-我在說的是“現在”啊
Find someone else.
去找別人吧
You wouldn't know how I feel.
妳不會明白我的心情的
Is that right?
是嗎？
I can say for certain now.
現在我可以很肯定地說出口了
I dislike you, after all.
我果然很討厭你，贊恩
Oh, yeah? Well then--
是嗎？既然如此…
So I will keep recruiting you no matter how long it takes.
所以我決定了 不管花多久時間都要拉你進來
It's scary how much you don't make sense.
妳莫名其妙到可怕的程度
Thank you. It's so warm.
謝謝，好溫暖喔
I am terribly sorry for all the trouble.
造成您的困擾真的很抱歉
Excuse me.
打擾了
How much did you buy it for?
妳花了多少錢買回來？
He said, "It's almost the harvest festival so enjoy your stay,"
他說：“豐收祭快到了 好好享受喔”
and gave it back for free.
然後就分文不收地還給我了
You're lucky they were nice people.
幸虧遇上了好人呢
They didn't know how to get rid of the axe.
他們不知道怎麼處理掉斧頭
How sad…
好難過…
Put these on, please.
修塔爾克大人，請穿上衣服吧
Why are you pinching it like it's something dirty?
那種像是拿髒東西的拿法是怎樣？
This is yours, Master Sein.
這是贊恩大人的衣服
What did I do to deserve this treatment?
我是做了什麼要被這樣對待啊？
She's mad that you stripped Stark of all his belongings.
她是氣你害修塔爾克輸到被扒光衣服
It wasn't me, it was the village chief.
又不是我的錯，明明是村長贏走的
People who gamble are the worst.
賭博的人最差勁了
I'm sorry.
對不起啦
Not to mention, Master Sein is a priest.
更不用說贊恩大人還是個僧侶
What about priests who drink alcohol?
那喝酒的僧侶怎麼樣？
You don't know, Mistress Frieren?
芙莉蓮大人難道不知道嗎？
Alcohol is the best medicine.
“酒為百藥之長”
Darn that Heiter… What in the world did he teach you?
海塔那傢伙 到底都教了妳些什麼東西啊？
Whether or not he joins us aside,
不管他是否要加入我們
I think Sein should still become an adventurer.
我認為贊恩應該要成為冒險者
Why are you so cooperative all of a sudden?
妳怎麼突然之間這麼配合啊？
I just thought it'd be nice to nudge someone once in a while.
我只是覺得偶爾推人家一把也不錯
Just as Himmel the Hero did.
就像勇者欣梅爾做過的那樣
Apparently,
看來
these adventurers
這些冒險者
have decided to stay in the village.
決定要在村子待上一段時日了
Ever since that day, they recruit me almost every day.
從那天起，他們幾乎每天都來邀請我
Even when I tried to make them give up,
就算我想逼他們放棄
it was to no avail.
也是徒勞無功
With eyes filled with hopes and dreams,
他們用充滿希望與夢想的雙眼來邀我
just like his were,
就如同過去的他一樣
they invite me to join their adventure.
邀請我加入他們的冒險
I'm only going to go around the northern lands a little.
我只是要去北方諸國轉轉
I'll be back by the harvest festival in three years.
三年後的豐收祭前就會回來
If you're not ready now, I'll wait until then.
如果你現在還沒準備好 我就等你到那個時候吧
Let's go on the next adventure together.
到時再一起去下一場冒險
Every time they recruit me, I think,
他們每次來邀請我，我都在想
"Why now, after all this time?"
“都過那麼久了，為何是現在？”
All of that is too blinding for me now.
對現在的我來說 那種事情太過耀眼了
What does Sein like?
贊恩喜歡的東西嗎？
We're having a hard time.
我們陷入苦戰了
So we want tips.
所以想參考一下
Let's see…
我想想看…
Drinking, smoking, gambling…
喝酒、抽菸、賭博…
We know that already.
那些我們都已經知道了
Is he really a priest?
那傢伙真的是僧侶？
So Master Heiter was an upstanding priest after all.
海塔大人果然是正派的僧侶呢
What counts as an "upstanding priest"?
正派僧侶的標準是什麼啊？
Other than that,
除了那些
he likes older ladies.
他喜歡年長的大姐姐
He's basically an apostate at this point.
這種程度已經算是破戒僧了吧
Older ladies, huh?
年長的大姐姐嗎？
Honestly though, what can we do with that information?
坦白說，拿到這種情報是能幹嘛？
What?
怎樣？
-Oh, that's right… -Brother!
-原來如此… -哥哥！
Isn't our new scythe a little too small?
新鐮刀也太小了吧？
We can't cut grass with this…
這種東西哪能除草…
You guys again?
又是你們？
Can you give us a second?
贊因，借一步說話
You're still here?
你還在啊？
Come on!
好了啦！
Look, how many times do I have to tell you?
拜託，我都說過幾次了？
Go find someone else.
去找別人吧
Sein,
贊恩
would you like to travel with an older lady?
你不想跟年長的大姐姐去旅行嗎？
Are you stupid?
你是笨蛋嗎？
That is exactly why I wanted to become an adventurer when I was a kid.
那就是我自小想成為冒險者的原因啊
What a horrible motive.
有夠不純潔的動機
So, where is she?
所以呢？在哪裡？
Where is this "older lady"?
年長的大姐姐在哪？
Right here, Sein.
在這裡喔，贊恩
I am an elf.
我是精靈
I am a lady much older than you.
是比你大上很多的大姐姐喔
My brother mentioned something like that before…
說起來，哥哥好像有說過這麼一回事
I refuse
這種…
to call that an older lady!
這種才不是什麼大姐姐！
He looks so distressed.
他看起來好悲痛
Oh, well…
沒辦法了
To tell the truth, I don't really like doing this, but…
老實說我一點 都不喜歡做這件事，不過…
It's time to show the seduction skills that I learned from my master.
是時候展現師父教我的美人計了
What was that?
那是什麼？
I blew you a kiss.
我給你送了個飛吻喔
I guess it was too advanced for a boy like you.
想來對你這種小男生來說還太早了
Can somebody please take this child home?
這誰家的孩子啊？快點帶回去吧
That was too sexy!
也太情色了！
What is up with you guys?
你們那是什麼反應？
That's weird…
真奇怪
When I tested it on Himmel, it was so effective that he fainted.
對欣梅爾施展這招的時候 明明有效到他昏過去的啊
-Himmel! -What a heartless woman.
-欣梅爾！ -罪孽深重的女人
-How strange… -I understand that feeling.
-好奇怪… -我明白了
If I had taken a direct hit, it would've knocked me out.
換作是我直接承受這一擊 也會昏過去的
I guess he really is a priest, after all.
所以就算是破戒僧也還是僧侶啊
-We've got ourselves a tough opponent. -That's enough!
-這是遇上強敵了 -不要再鬧了！
I have no intention of becoming an adventurer.
我並不打算成為冒險者
Don't you want to go after your best friend?
你不想追上自己的摯友嗎？
Brother, you should understand.
哥哥應該明白我的想法吧
Sein…
贊恩…
He said that he would come back in three years.
那傢伙說過三年後就會回來
But it's been ten years since then.
自那之後都過了十年了
Obviously, he's dead already.
想必他已經死了
You're going to give up without even finding him?
你找都不找就要放棄了？
It's only been ten years.
不過才十年而已
If you don't go find him now, you'll regret it in the near future.
如果你現在不去找他 不久的將來你就會後悔的
You'll think, "What if it wasn't too late?"
你會想著 “那時出發的話也許還來得及”
Why…
都過…
I bet you're thinking, "Why now after all this time?"
“都過那麼久了，為何是現在？” 你是這麼想的吧？
I'm talking about what you can do "now,"
我說的是你“現在”能做的事情啊
Sein.
贊恩
I can't go. It's for the same reason
去不了，理由還是跟
I didn't go along with him ten years ago.
十年前我沒跟他一起走時一樣
There's no way I could leave the village
我不可能丟下村子
and leave my brother behind.
更不可能放下哥哥不管
What are you talking about, Sein?
你在說什麼，贊恩？
When Master Heiter came to visit from the Holy City,
海塔大人從聖都來訪察的時候
I overheard you…
我聽到了你們的談話
Someone as talented as you
像你這樣能幹的僧侶
should have no problem serving as a priest in the Holy City.
就是到聖都服務也沒有問題
In the Holy City?
我去聖都嗎？
Yes, I'm sure of it.
沒錯，我敢保證
Master Heiter, what would happen to my little brother then?
海塔大人，那我弟弟會怎麼樣？
He can come to the Holy City too.
當然是一起來聖都
I see.
這樣啊
Master Heiter, I appreciate the offer,
海塔大人，謝謝您的邀請
but I have no issues with my life in this village.
但我在這個村子裡的生活無虞
My little brother lost his parents when he was young.
我弟弟在很小的時候就沒了父母
As his older brother,
作為他的兄長
I can't possibly rob him of his hometown as well.
我不能連他的故鄉都剝奪掉
Is that so?
是這樣嗎？
I understand your decision.
我明白你的心情了
I guess I came here for nothing.
看來是白走一趟了呢
But since I'm here anyway,
不過既然我都來了
I'll have your little brother
就順道給你弟弟
listen to all the stories from my adventures.
講講我當年的冒險故事吧
My brother stayed in this village because of me.
哥哥當年是因為我才留在村子
Sein, that is what you were thinking all this time?
贊恩，你一直以來都是這麼想的嗎？
Don't act like we're the same!
別把我跟你相提並論！
I have never regretted my decision. Not even once!
我從未後悔過我的決定 一次都沒有過！
Look at you, on the other hand.
反過來看看你
How long do you plan to drown in regret?
你打算沉浸在後悔裡多久？
I'm done with you.
真是夠了
I apologized to my brother.
我向哥哥道歉了
I don't want you to get the wrong idea.
你們不要誤會了
He's really kind.
哥哥他真的是很溫柔的人
He's never hit me before.
以前他從來沒打過我
I'm the one who pushed him to that point.
把那樣的哥哥逼到動手的人是我
I've never seen that expression on his face.
他那種表情我還是第一次見到
Frieren, I've decided to become an adventurer.
芙莉蓮，我決定要成為冒險者了
I'll chase after him.
我要去追他
It's only been ten years, after all.
畢竟才過了十年而已
I see.
這樣啊
The objective of my journey is to find him.
我這趟旅程的目的是要找到那傢伙
I will find him
我會找到那傢伙
and fulfill the silly dream I had as a kid.
然後實現兒時那無聊的夢想
So it's temporary.
所以這只是暫時的
I'll join you temporarily.
我會暫時跟你們同行
-I did it! -You did it!
-釣到了！ -你釣到了呢！
Bye!
再見了！
Have a safe trip!
一路平安喔！
By the way, what's the goal of your journey?
話說回來，你們旅途的目的地是哪？
Heaven.
天國
Why go out of your way to travel there?
為什麼要特地去那裡？
Anybody can go once you die.
死了之後誰都會去那裡吧
Even you, Sein?
贊恩也是嗎？
Is it just me, or is that girl really harsh?
怎麼感覺那孩子攻擊性很強啊？
We can do this together.
一起加油吧
What is going on?
這是怎樣啊？
How do you deal with others?
人跟人之間的距離感是什麼？
I think I'd die.
我還以為死定了
-Let's go shopping. -It's all about helping each other.
-一起去買禮物吧 -彼此會互相幫助
Do you hate me that much?
妳就那麼討厭我嗎？
"Privilege of the Young".
《年輕人的特權》
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯：洪貞韻